(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-14T00:56:32.865480",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
白いドレス
A white dress,
花が舞う胸に
flowers fluttering on my chest...
世界一の
I swear to you
愛を誓う
the world's greatest love.
みんな見てて
"Look, everyone,"
一番綺麗？
"am I the most beautiful?"
君の不意打ち
Your sudden surprise...
意地悪な人
you're so teasing.
いつもより
You look a bit cooler
かっこいいかも
than usual today.
気のせいですか？
"Is it just my imagination?"
二人は笑う
We both laugh.
紹介したい
"There's someone
人がいるんだ
I want to introduce you to."
パパとママと同じ
Just like Mom and Dad,
負けず嫌いな
they hate to lose,
涙もろくよく笑う
easily moved to tears, quick to laugh,
優しい人なんだって
and such a kind person, they say.
歩いてもいいですか？
"May we walk together?"
エスコートしてよね
"Please escort me!"
君は「はい」と
You say, "Yes,"
離さないでね
and never let me go.
世界一の
I'll give you
愛をあげる
the world's greatest love.
喧嘩しても
Even if we fight,
落ち込んでも
or feel down,
君の味方
I'll always be on your side.
愛に出会い
Meeting love,
君がいるなら 恋は続く
if you are here, this love will continue.
運命の人は来ない
"My destined prince won't come," they say,
白馬に乗ってやってきました
yet he arrived riding on a white horse.
現実はそうじゃないけど
Reality isn't like that,
普通の君が一番好きよ
but I love the ordinary you the best.
紹介したい人がいます
There is someone I want to introduce.
不釣り合いかな？ 慣れない君
We might be mismatched, you're not used to this.
緊張して噛んじゃうのも
You're nervous and tripping over your words,
来てくれてありがとう
but thank you for coming.
誓ってもいいですか？
Can I make a vow?
浮気しないでね
Please don't cheat on me, okay?
君のために歌っておいたの
I sang this song for you,
世界一のドレス姿
wearing the world's most beautiful dress.
小指の糸 ほどけないよね
The thread on our pinky fingers won't unravel, right?
ぎゅっと強く愛を編んで
Tightly and strongly, we weave our love,
君の隣 恋は続く
at your side, this love will continue.
笑って決めていたの
We laughed and made up our minds,
パパの涙が伝っちゃうじゃん保存する
or else Dad's tears will start flowing.
君は凛として笑う
You smile with a dignified look,
幸せをありがとう
thank you for the happiness.
目を閉じていいですか？
May I close my eyes?
大好きでいてよね
Keep loving me always, okay?
君はナイト 離さないでね
You are my knight, don't ever let me go.
世界一の愛をあげる
I'll give you the world's greatest love.
喧嘩しても 落ち込んでても
Even if we fight or if I feel down,
君の味方 愛に出会い
I'll be on your side. Meeting love,
君がいるなら 恋は続く
if you are here, this love will continue.
というわけで、こんかぷー！
And with that, Kon-kapu!
魔界の天才ヴァンパイア、夜空メルです！
I'm the genius vampire from the underworld, Yozora Mel!
いぇーい！みんな盛り上がってますかー？
Yay! Is everyone excited?
もうメルがね、ホロライブに来てから5年目みたいなんです。
It seems it's already my fifth year since joining Hololive.
いや、なんか早いようでね、長いようで…短い、ってやつなんですけども。
Well, it feels like it's been fast... wait, long?
It's that "feels long yet short" kind of thing.
なのでね、今回もいっぱい歌って踊るので、
So, I'll be singing and dancing a lot this time as well,
最後まで楽しんでってくださーい！
so please enjoy it until the very end!
見ててね、ゲストもこの後、あのたくさんね、お呼びしてるので、楽しんでってくださーい！
Also, I've invited many guests for later,
so look forward to that and enjoy!
そして、えー今回はも、ハッシュタグあります。
And also, we have a hashtag for this stream.
「夜空メル5周年」で、いっぱいスクショとかツイートとか、
Please post lots of screenshots and tweets with
#YozoraMel5thAnniversary,
してくれると嬉しいなぁ、トレンドまで届けてほしいなぁ、チラッ。チラッ。
I'd be so happy, and I hope we can trend!
*peek* *peek*
よろしくお願いします！
Please do!
それじゃあ、この後も夜空メルをいっぱい見てってね！
Well then, please keep watching lots of
Yozora Mel after this too!
続きはウェブで！
Find out the rest on the web!
俺の名前はかぶ太郎。
My name is Kabutarou.
今日は魔界から来たヴァンパイア、夜空メルとデートである。
Today, I have a date with Yozora Mel,
a vampire from the underworld.
みてみて！めっちゃきれいじゃない？
Look, look! Isn't it super pretty?
彼女が目を輝かせた先にあったのは、ショーウィンドウに飾られた白い綺麗なドレスだった。
What caught her sparkling eyes was a beautiful
white dress displayed in the shop window.
［選択肢］
1. こういうの興味あるんだ？
2. メルのほうが綺麗だよ
3. そんなことよりお腹すいたよ
[Choices]
1. Are you interested in this kind of thing?
2. Mel, you are prettier
3. More importantly, I'm hungry
こういうの興味あるんだ？
Are you interested in this kind of thing?
んー、女の子なら一度は憧れるんじゃない？
Hmm, wouldn't any girl dream of it
at least once?
メルって黒のイメージあるじゃん？こういう白いドレスも着てみたいな〜なんて！
I usually have a dark image, right?
So I thought it'd be nice to wear a white dress like this... just kidding!
（本音なのか照れ隠しなのか全く掴めない…が、彼女がドレスを着てみたいことだけはわかった。）
(I can't tell if she's being honest or just embarrassed...
but I do know she wants to wear that dress.)
…覚えとくよ
...I'll keep that in mind.
ん？今なんか言った？
Hmm? Did you say something just now?
（深夜アニメの主人公かな？立…）
(Am I a late-night anime protagonist? ...)
本当は聞こえてたけどね
Actually, I could hear you, you know.
愛してる 聞こえてる? 君の番
"I love you," can you hear me? Your turn.
愛してる
"I love you."
風の日も 雨の日も Ah...
On windy days and rainy days, ah...
ずっとそばに
I'll always be by your side.
すれ違う金曜日
Passing each other by on Friday.
口をきかない土曜日
Not speaking to each other on Saturday.
曖昧になってく理由
The reasons start to blur.
なんとなく戻って日曜日
Somehow getting back on track on Sunday.
ごめんなさいは一緒に口にしてる
Saying "I'm sorry" together.
誰かが言っていた
Someone once said...
愛は育つの遅いらしい
...that love takes a long time to grow.
ほら ほら
Look, look...
言葉にしてよ
...put it into words...
もう1回
...one more time.
愛してる 聞こえてる? 君の番
"I love you," can you hear me? Your turn.
愛してる
"I love you."
風の日も 雨の日も
On windy days and rainy days...
ひと笑いしましょう
...let's share a laugh.
忘れないように
So that we never forget...
螺旋階段の夕焼け
...the sunset on the spiral staircase.
広くても 狭くても
Whether it's spacious or cramped...
ずっとそばに居る
...I'll always be by your side.
君
You.
壊れかけていたインターホン
The half-broken intercom.
シミの付いた壁紙
The stained wallpaper.
荷造り
Packing...
重なったダンボール
...and stacked cardboard boxes.
どこ切り取っても思い出がよみがえる
Wherever I look, memories come flooding back.
新居が楽しみだね
I'm looking forward to our new home.
誰かが言っていた
Someone once said...
幸福とは人愛すること
...that happiness is loving someone.
ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey...
約束しよう
...let's promise...
永遠に
...forever.
愛してる 聞こえてる? 君の番
"I love you," can you hear me? Your turn.
愛してる
"I love you."
病める日も 健やかなる日も
In sickness and in health...
ひと笑いしましょう
...let's share a laugh.
この先何十年
For the decades to come...
繋がっていくミライチズ
...our future map will connect us.
歳をとっても 皺が増えても
Even as we age and get wrinkles...
ずっとそばに居る
...I'll always be by your side.
君
You.
歌いたい 語りたい 見ていたい
I want to sing, I want to talk, I want to watch.
歌いたい 甘えたい ふざけたい
I want to sing, I want to be spoiled, I want to goof off.
一緒に映画観て泣きたい 君と
I want to watch a movie and cry together with you.
この先何が起こったとして
No matter what happens in the future...
変わらないことはたった一つ
...only one thing will never change.
君が好き
I love you.
愛してる 聞こえてる? 君の番
"I love you," can you hear me? Your turn.
愛してる
"I love you."
風の日も 雨の日も
On windy days and rainy days...
ひと笑いしましょう
...let's share a laugh.
忘れないように
So that we never forget...
螺旋階段の夕焼け
...the sunset on the spiral staircase.
広くても 狭くても
Whether it's spacious or cramped...
ずっと
...always...
愛してる 聞こえてる? 君の番
"I love you," can you hear me? Your turn.
愛してる
"I love you."
病める日も 健やかなる日も
In sickness and in health...
ひと笑いしましょう
...let's share a laugh.
この先何十年
For the decades to come...
繋がっていくミライチズ
...our future map will connect us.
歳をとっても 皺が増えても
Even as we age and get wrinkles...
ずっとそばに居る
...I'll always be by your side.
君
You.
はい！ということでメル様！
And with that, Mel-sama!
5周年おめでとう！ / ありがとう！
Congratulations on your 5th anniversary! / Thank you!
イェーイ！メルキッスです！ / ともとも！
Yay! It's Melkiss! / Tomotomo!
5周年
5th anniversary...
せっかくベンチがあるからさ、一緒に座らない？
Since there's a bench right here, why don't we sit together?
そんな、メル様から誘っていただけるなんて、恐縮です！
Oh my, for Mel-sama to invite me, I'm honored!
踊って疲れたでしょ？
You must be tired from dancing, right?
いえ、全然疲れてないです！
No, I'm not tired at all!
あれ？じゃあ座ろうよ、せっかくだし、お花見しようよ、お花見！
Oh really? Well, let's sit down anyway! Let's view the cherry blossoms!
メル様とお花見できるのめちゃめちゃ嬉しいです！
I'm so incredibly happy to view the cherry blossoms with you!
やったー！ / やったー！
Yay! / Yay!
よいしょっと
Up we go.
よいしょ。
わあー！桜綺麗だね！ / ねえ、綺麗！
Wow! The cherry blossoms are beautiful! / Yes, beautiful!
きれい！
Beautiful!
でも、チョコ先生の方がきれいだよ。
But you're more beautiful, Choco-sensei.
えっそんな、そんなこと言わないでよ、メル様！もう！
Eh, don't say that, Mel-sama! Geez!
メル様、桜に囲まれてちょっと、いつも以上に可愛い！
Mel-sama, surrounded by cherry blossoms, you're even cuter than usual!
ねえ！ありがとう、チョコ先生！
Aw, thank you, Choco-sensei!
あ、可愛い。ちょっとファンサしなさいよ、ほら。
Ah, cute. Come on, do some fan service.
あ、いいよいいよ、あ、いいよいいよ！投げキッスしたって、もう。
Ah, fine, fine! Ah, fine, fine! I even blew a kiss, really.
おっとっとっと、チョコ、チョコ先生も。
Whoops, you too, Choco-sensei.
あ、もっと、もっとチュウして。ほら。
Ah, kiss me more, more. Come on.
メルが？
Me?
もっと。足りない。
More. It's not enough.
もう！
Geez!
チョコ先生もっと近く行っていい？
Choco-sensei, can I get closer?
え？もっと近く？
Eh? Closer?
ちょっと遠いじゃん。
We're a bit far apart.
ほら、一人分空いてるし。
See, there's space for one person here.
あ、ね？いいよ。
Ah, right? Sure.
もしもし。 もしもし。
"Hello?" "Hello?"
もうちょっと近く。
A bit closer.
もうちょっと？
A bit more?
よいしょ。
Here we go.
近い、近い。
So close, so close.
今、スクショタイムだぞ。
Now is screenshot time!
ドキドキ。
My heart is pounding.
アニメが始まりそうである。
It feels like an anime is about to start.
エモい。
So aesthetic.
エモいぞ。こうかしら、こうだな。
Aesthetic. Like this? Yes, like this.
チョコ先生、実はさ、メルね、料理教室に最近通ってるんですよ。
Choco-sensei, actually, I've been attending cooking classes lately.
え？それって、はあちゃまの料理教室？
Eh? Is that Haachama's cooking class?
はあちゃま？いや、はあちゃまに料理習ったら料理じゃないんだよね。
Haachama? No, if you learn from Haachama, it's no longer cooking.
だって、メルメルクッキング？もっと違う、メルメルクッキング...
Because, Melmel Cooking? Or rather, Melmel Cooking...
違うよ、普通の料理だよ。
No, it's not. It's normal cooking.
え？食べれる料理を作るってこと？
Eh? You mean making edible food?
前も食べれてたわ！
It was edible before too!
ガチ？
Seriously?
いや、だってほら、チョコ先生、いつも誰かにさ、作ってあげてるでしょ？
Well, you see, Choco-sensei, you're always cooking for someone, right?
まあ、確かにね。
Well, that's true.
だから、今度はチョコ先生のためにメルが作ってさ、帰ってきたときにほら、ご飯あったら嬉しくない？
So this time, I will cook for you, and wouldn't you be happy if dinner was ready when you came home?
え？ってことは、チョコが疲れて「ただいま」って帰ってきて、
Eh? So that means when I come home tired, saying "I'm home,"
そしたら「あれ？なんかいい匂いがする」って言って、
and then think, "Oh, what's that nice smell?"
リビング行ったら、メル様が、え？
And when I go to the living room, Mel-sama is... eh?
そうだよ。「お帰りなさい」って。
That's right. Saying, "Welcome home."
お帰りなさいからの？
From "Welcome home" to?
からの、ご飯にする？
To, "Would you like dinner?"
お風呂にする？メルにする？
"Would you like a bath? Or... me?"
いや、もうそんなのご飯に決まってるじゃないですか！
No, of course dinner is the obvious choice!
メル様、最高！おい！
Mel-sama, you're the best! Hey!
いや、いいよ、奥さんだ、それはもう、マジ、ガチで。
No, it's nice, you're like a wife, seriously, for real.
嬉しい！
I'm happy!
やっぱ、持つべきヴァンパイアは、やっぱメル様なのよ。
After all, Mel-sama is the vampire to have.
いや、それほどでも。
No, not that much.
チョコ先生、今年はさ、一緒にお風呂入りませんか？
Choco-sensei, this year, why don't we take a bath together?
ん？
Hm?
お風呂。
A bath.
お風呂？ お風呂！？
A bath? "A bath!?"
だって、メルティキッスさ、もう結構長いじゃん、付き合い。
Because MelKiss has had a pretty long relationship now, right?
まあ、確かにね。
Well, that's true.
なのに、まだお風呂も、一緒に寝たこともないんだよ。
And yet, we've never taken a bath or slept together.
あ、そうよね。え？今までお風呂入ったのって誰と？
Ah, that's true. Eh? Who have you taken a bath with so far?
え、こより？
Eh, Koyori?
ああ、こより様と。
Ah, Koyori-sama.
スバルとも寝た。シオンとも、マリンとも寝たけど、まだチョコ先生と何もしてないんだよ。
I've slept with Subaru, Shion, and Marine, but I haven't done anything with you yet.
そうですよね。
That's true.
そうだよ。
It is.
チョコはずっと待ってるのに。
Even though I've been waiting all this time.
え？待ってる？だって、それ言ったら、チョコ先生とは、ちゃんと時間作って一緒にするって言ったのに。
Eh? Waiting? But you said we'd make proper time to do it together...
あれ？メル待ちだったってこと？
Huh? You mean you were waiting for me?
チョコ、ずっと待ってたの！
I was waiting all this time!
チョコ先生からも来ないよ。メルだって待ってるのに。
You didn't make a move either. Even though I was waiting too.
本当に？
Really?
うん。
Yeah.
だって、でもそしたら二番目の女になっちゃう。
But if I do, I'll become the second woman.
二番目の女？
The second woman?
チョコが一番だよ。
You're number one.
何その顔？
What's with that face?
チョコも一番の女になりたいからさ。
Because I want to be your number one woman too.
え？ホロメンとはまだ旅行行ってない？
Eh? Have you not gone on a trip with other Holomembers yet?
あ、行ってないかも。大人数では行ったけどさ、二人きりのはない。
Ah, maybe not. We went in a large group, but not just the two of us.
二人の旅行行ってないってこと？
So you haven't gone on a two-person trip?
行ってない。
We haven't.
メル様、今年メルキス、お泊り旅行行きます！
Mel-sama, this year, MelKiss is going on an overnight trip!
やった！言質取りました！
Yay! I got you on record!
あ、もうこんな時間だ。ちょっと待って、メル、このあと用事があるんだよね。
Ah, it's already this time. Wait, I have some business after this.
え？誰と？
Eh? With whom?
え、あ、ねねちと。
Eh, ah, with Nene-chi.
他の女と用事？
Business with another woman?
あ、やべ。じゃ、ちょっとそろそろ行ってくるわ。
Ah, shoot. Well, I should head off soon.
メル様、チョコ。
Mel-sama, what about me?
じゃあね。
See ya.
ちょっと待って！旅行まだ決めてないよ！
Wait a minute! We haven't decided on the trip yet!
可愛くてごめん
[Song: Sorry for being cute]
私が私のこと愛して何が悪いの？
What's wrong with me loving myself?
嫉妬でしょうか？
Is it jealousy?
痛いだとか変わってるとか
Saying it's cringy or weird...
届きませんね、その陰口
That bad-mouthing doesn't reach me!
大好きな洋服
My favorite clothes,
大好きなお化粧で
with my favorite makeup,
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて
curling my usual half-twin tails,
お出かけしよ
let's go out!
日傘持ってぼうしかぶって
With my parasol and hat on,
ぬいぐるみ連れて行こう
let's bring along a plushie.
ちゅ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute!
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born!
ちゅ！あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculatingly cute!
気になっちゃうよね？ごめん
You can't help but notice me, right? Sorry!
ちゅ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute!
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working so hard!
ちゅ！尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious!
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having such high feminine charm!
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまぁ
It pisses you off, right? Serves you right!
あなたはあなたのことだけどうぞ
You should just worry about yourself,
私に干渉しないでください(>_<)
please don't meddle in my business.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけど
They say birds of a feather flock together,
届きませんね、その陰口
but those insults don't reach me.
重いリップグロス
Heavy lip gloss,
お気に入りのチークで
with my favorite blush,
崩せない前髪櫛で梳いて
combing my bangs to keep them perfect,
お出かけしよ
let's go out!
軽い女？ふざけんな
An easy girl? Don't make me laugh.
重すぎるっつーの
I'm way too heavy, you know!
ちゅ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute!
この時代生きてごめん
Sorry for living in this era!
ちゅ！目立っててごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out!
意識しちゃうよね？ごめん
You're totally conscious of me, right? Sorry!
ちゅ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute!
自分磨きしてごめん
Sorry for polishing myself!
ちゅ！ぶりっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for playing dumb-cute!
虜にしちゃってごめん
Sorry for captivating you!
ムカついちゃうでしょ？ざまぁ
You must be pissed off, right? Serves you right!
趣味の違い、変わり者と
Differences in tastes, calling me a weirdo...
馬鹿にされても
Even if I'm made fun of for that,
曲げたくない、怖くもない
I won't bend, and I'm not afraid.
あんたらことき
Not by people like you!
自分の味方は自分でありたい
I want to be my own biggest ally.
一番大切にしてあげたい
I want to cherish myself the most.
理不尽な我慢はさせたくない
I don't want to make myself endure unreasonable things.
それが、私
Because that is... me!
ちゅ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute!
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born!
ちゅ！あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculatingly cute!
人生楽しんでごめん
Sorry for enjoying my life!
ちゅ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute!
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working so hard!
ちゅ！尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious!
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having such high feminine charm!
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまぁ
It pisses you off, right? Serves you right!
おねだりしてみて欲しいの
I want you to try begging me.
おねがいダーリン
Please, Darling!
[Song: Please, Darling]
ダーリンあなたって本当に私の話全然聞かない！
Darling, you really don't listen to anything I say!
あれほどやめてって言ったのに
Even though I told you to stop so many times!
どうするの？申し訳ないと思ってないでしょ本当に
What are you going to do? You're not even sorry, are you? Seriously!
覚悟決めて！社会になっても甘やしてあげないんだから！
Get ready! Even in society, I won't pamper you!
あれやこれや言ったってどうにもならない あなたのハートは真っ黒で
No matter what I say, it's no use. Your heart is pitch black!
言いたいことは言わないし
You don't say what you want to say,
やりたいことだけやりたい放題
yet you do whatever you want!
そんなのバカみたいじゃない
Isn't that just foolish?
そうじゃない？じゃない？じゃない？
Isn't that right? Right? Right?
ねえ、お互いの気持ち感じて
Hey, feel each other's feelings,
察して欲しい感じて
feel how I want you to understand!
わざと口にしないの、ずるくない？
Deliberately not saying it... isn't that unfair?
バカじゃないの？
Are you stupid?
おねがいダーリン、見て聞いて
Please, Darling, look and listen!
欲しいのは形のないもの
What I want is something formless.
馬鹿にしないで、見て聞いて
Don't make fun of me, look and listen!
覗いてよ、瞳の奥の方
Peer into the depths of my eyes.
真っ直ぐ見つめて
Stare straight at me.
おねだりしてみて欲しいの
I want you to try begging me.
ダーリン、私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ。あれほどキャピキャピ見つめてきたのに今ではすっかり知らんぷり！
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all. Even though you used to stare at me so excitedly, now you completely ignore me!
ていうかそれってあぐらかいてるだけなんじゃないですか？
I mean, aren't you just resting on your laurels?
ぶっちゃけ死活問題、あなたのおかげで私のハートはボロボロです！
Frankly, it's a matter of life and death, because of you my heart is in tatters!
すれ違いいつもすれ違い
Missing each other, always missing each other.
どっちの気持ちも言い出さないからいつも私が空回り
Since neither of us says how we feel, I'm always running in circles.
なんだかバカみたいじゃない？そう、そんなことない？楽しいの？
Isn't it kind of stupid? Is it not like that? Is it fun?
どこか足元見てる感じで
It feels like you're looking down on me somehow,
ラブみ冷めてる感じで
feels like our love has cooled down.
駆け引き？やだ　こっちもケチじゃなくなーい？
Mind games? No way, isn't it stingy on my end too?
そういうめんどくさいことしてるから、めんどくさいことになるんだよ！
Doing those annoying things is why things get so annoying!
おねがいダーリン　見て聞いて　寂しさは飾りじゃないのよ
Please, Darling, look and listen. My loneliness isn't just for show.
よそ見しないで　逃げないで　触ってよ　心の奥の方
Don't look away, don't run away. Touch the depth of my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない　おねだりしてみてはくれないの？
It's not just for a moment. Won't you try pleading with me?
言葉にできない臆病さは
The cowardice that cannot be put into words
したたかさではないのよ
is not calculation.
甘えてないで口に出してよ
Don't just rely on me, say it out loud.
もう、ちゃんとこっち向いてってば！
Geez, look over here already!
おねがいダーリン　見て聞いて　欲しいのはカタチのないもの
Please, Darling, look and listen. What I want is something with no shape.
バカにしないで　見て聞いて　覗いてよ　瞳の奥の方
Don't make fun of me, look and listen. Peek into the depths of my eyes.
甘くないダーリン　ねだらないで　暴いてよ　私の素顔
My sweet-less Darling, don't plead, uncover my true face.
おねがいダーリン　そばにいて　触らせて　心の奥の方
Please, Darling, stay by my side, let me touch the depth of your heart.
真っ直ぐ見つめて　おねだりしてみてほしいの
Stare straight at me, I want you to try pleading with me.
おねがいダーリン！
Please, Darling!
いぇーい！ うおおおー！
Yay! Woooo!
魔界の天才ヴァンパイア、ホロライブ1期生の夜空メルでーす！
The genius vampire of the demon realm, Yozora Mel from hololive 1st generation!
えー、ホロライブ界の天才ヴァンパイア…あ、5期生の桃鈴ねねでーす！
Um, the genius vampire of the hololive world... ah, Momosuzu Nene from 5th generation!
二人合わせてー
Together we are...
せーの、ねねメルねるねるねーす！
One, two, Nene-Mel Nelnelnes!
完璧じゃん！ いいじゃん！ やったー！
That was perfect! That's great! Yay!
この前のバカライブで鍛えられたの？
Did you train for this in that stupid live show earlier?
ね、すごい鍛えられてた。楽しかったねー！
Yeah, I was trained a lot. That was fun!
ってか、メル先輩、5周年！ / そうだよ、5周年だよー！
By the way, Mel-senpai, your 5th anniversary! / That's right, 5th anniversary!
すごーい！おめでとー！ / ありがとう、5周年、いぇーい！
Amazing! Congratulations! / Thank you, 5th anniversary, yay!
え、なんか今回のロゴめっちゃ可愛い。なんかちょっとシックな感じもあって。
Oh, the logo this time is super cute. It has a slightly chic feel to it too.
そうなんだよ。ちょっとウェディングっぽい感じ。
That's right. It has a bit of a wedding-like feel.
あ、ぽいぽいぽい！なんかお菓子みたいなイメージだね。 / そうだね、ケーキも後ろにあるしね。
Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah! It feels kind of like candy. / Right, we also have a cake behind us.
あ、ね！お城すごいね、メルちゃん、ね！ / 見えてないけど、いぇーい！
Ah, right! The castle is amazing, Mel-chan, right! / I can't see it, but yay!
ちょっとね、これからもね、大先輩なんですけど、ちょっと... / これ何ですか、これ？
Since you're my great senpai, from now on too, um... / What is this?
これ、ごま（胡麻）すってる、これ？ / すって、すってないです、いやでもね、これからも...
Are you brown-nosing me with this? / I-I'm not brown-nosing! But seriously, from now on too...
よろしくお願いしますよー！ / 後輩、よろしくね。
I'll be in your care! / As my kouhai, I'll count on you.
後輩として、よろしくね。あ、ありがとうございます！よろしくね！ / うん、よろしくねー。
As your kouhai, I count on you. Ah, thank you! I'm in your care! / Yeah, I look forward to it too.
じゃあ、メル先輩、まだまだね、これからもういっぱい、やることがあると思うので。 / ありますとも！まだまだ！
So, Mel-senpai, you still have plenty of things to do from here on, I think. / I certainly do! Still plenty!
では、帰りましょうかね？ / え？帰るの？ / がんばって！がんばってね！
Shall we go home now? / Eh? Go home? / Do your best! Good luck!
ありがとう。え、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ！待って、待って！ / おいおいおい、何々何ー？
Thank you. Eh, wait, wait, wait! Wait a minute! / Hey, hey, what is it?
まだ帰さないよ。 / きゃっ！
I'm not letting you go home yet. / Kya!
カプ民、起きなさいよ！
Kapu-min, wake up already!
Teammates, wake up!
風真隊、起きてください！
Kazama-tai, please wake up!
ロゼ隊、起きて！
Rose-tai, wake up!
ねっ友、起きて！
Nettomo, wake up!
喜びも
Our joys,
悲しみも
and our sorrows,
あなたと分け合え
let's share them with you
五等分で
divided into five parts.
1つ、作り笑いも見破られ
One: You saw right through my fake smile,
2つ、あんたなんか大嫌いよ
Two: I absolutely hate you,
3つ、真っ直ぐなこの気持ち気づいて
Three: Please notice these straightforward feelings of mine,
4つ、気がつくとだんだん
Four: Before I knew it, gradually...
5つ、分かり合えたね
Five: We came to understand each other,
勉強だけじゃなくて
It's not just about studying,
君を知りたいよ
I want to get to know you.
大嫌いから
From "I hate you",
大好きへと
to "I love you",
変わる心についていけないよ
I can't keep up with my changing heart.
どんなことも
No matter what it is,
あなたさえ
as long as it's with you,
五等分です　でも私は...
it's divided into five parts. But as for me...
私、私は
As for me, as for me...
あなたが好きよ
I love you.
少し複雑に心の中
A little complicated inside my heart,
でも変わってゆく気持ち
but my feelings are changing.
ずっとこんな関係続いていたらいいのにな
I wish this kind of relationship could last forever.
忘れられない思い出も
Memories I can't forget,
これから増えるストーリーも
and the stories that will increase from now on...
あなたなしだったら
If it weren't for you,
意味がない
there would be no point,
だめよ
no way.
ずっとそばで教えてね
Always stay by my side and teach me, okay?
だけど勝手に胸の鼓動高鳴る
But my heart starts racing on its own.
運命だって信じられる
I can even believe in destiny.
同じ気持ちね
We feel the same, don't we?
またいつか いつか いつか いつか
Will we dream of it again someday, someday,
夢に見るかな
someday, someday?
少しずつ変わる思い
My feelings are changing little by little.
焦りや苛立ち和らいでく
My impatience and irritation are softening.
信じきれる自信
The confidence to fully believe.
胸の奥に隠れてる言葉
The words hidden deep inside my heart,
甘えたいだけどいいですかって
I want to depend on you, but is that okay?
私、付いて行くわ
I will follow you.
いつまでも
Forever,
忘れない
I won't forget.
出会えた奇跡
The miracle of our meeting,
偶然じゃない そうでしょ？
it wasn't a coincidence, right?
大嫌いから 大好きへと
From hate to love,
変わる心に付いて行きたいよ
I want to keep up with my changing heart.
どんなことも
No matter what,
あなたさえ
as long as you're here,
克服する
we can overcome anything.
でも私 私 私 私 私は
But as for me, me, me, me, as for me...
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと あなたに
Always, always, always, always to you...
愛を誓います
I swear my love.
We are the bride
We are the bride, We are the bride
Please
いぇーい！
Yay!
サンキュー、サンキュー！
Thank you, thank you!
すごい！この曲、あれか！五等分の花嫁の曲だよね！
Awesome! This song is that, right? The song from The Quintessential Quintuplets!
そうだよー！
That's right!
どうして今日この5人が集められたか、みんな分かる？
Does everyone know why the five of us were gathered today?
え、なんでなんで？
Eh, why, why?
全然わかんない
I have no idea.
わかんないー
I don't know.
頭を見るんだ
Look at our heads.
頭？
Our heads?
ヘッド、ヘッド！
Heads, heads!
頭？
Heads?
ヘッドドレス！
Head dresses!
あー！
Ah!
ヘッドドレスだ！
It's head dresses!
そう、この5人、ヘッドドレスがお揃いだから、歌いたかったんだ
Right! Since we all have matching head dresses, I wanted us to sing together.
おおー！うれしい！
Oooh! I'm so glad!
ということはさ、でも、この曲だと
Which means... but, with this song,
私たちの中から1人選んでもらわなきゃいけないんじゃないの？
doesn't he have to choose one of us?
え、うそ！
Wait, really?!
アピールしなきゃ！
We have to show off!
選んで！
Choose me!
ちょっとちょっと！待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
今日は5周年なんだから<
Today is my 5th anniversary,
メルの特権！
so Mel has special privilege!
メルが選ばれるってこと！
Mel gets to be chosen!
えー！
What?!
ずるい！
No fair!
選ばせて！
Let us be chosen!
いいよ、いいよ
Fine, fine.
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
じゃあ、おめでとう！
Well then, congratulations!
いぇーい！
Yay!
おまたせ！遅くなってごめんね
Sorry to keep you waiting! Sorry I'm late.
大丈夫だよ！今日はなにしてたの？
It's okay! What were you doing today?
今日はね！ちょこ先生とねねちと〜
Today, you see! I was with Choco-sensei and Nenechi...
ってことがあってさ！めっちゃ楽しかったよ！
...and that happened! It was super fun!
(楽しそうに話すメルを見て微笑ましい反面、少しもやもした感情になってしまった。)
(While it's heartwarming to see Mel talking so happily, I felt a bit conflicted.)
(せっかく時間を作ってくれてるのにこんなんじゃダメだな)
(She made time for me, so I shouldn't be like this.)
んー？なんかあった？
Hmm? Did something happen?
(うまく隠してたつもりだったけどどうやら気づかれたようだ。)
(I thought I hid it well, but she noticed.)
(なんでわかるんだろう…)
(How does she know...)
えっな、なんで？
Eh, how...?
そりゃあ君のことちゃんーと見てますから！わかるよ？
Well, that's because I'm always looking closely at you! Of course I'd know.
…いや、その。僕といるときもちゃんと楽しめてるのかなって…
...No, well. I was wondering if you're really enjoying yourself when you're with me...
もう！楽しいに決まってるでしょ！じゃなかったらこんなおしゃれして…
Geez! Of course I'm having fun! If I wasn't, I wouldn't have dressed up like this...
一週間前からずっと楽しみになんかしてないってば！
...and I wouldn't have been looking forward to this since a week ago!
(頬を膨らませて怒るメルを見て不謹慎だけど僕は安心した。)
(Seeing Mel pout in anger, although it's inappropriate, I felt relieved.)
(Seeing Mel puff out her cheeks in anger, it was inappropriate, but I felt relieved.)
ていうか君もそういうこと考えるんだね
I mean, you think about those kinds of things too.
え？
Eh?
ううん、いつもそういうの隠すからさ！  ふふ、可愛いとこあるね～
No, it's just that you always hide that side of yourself! Hehe, you have your cute moments.
あのさ、この間ドレス着てみたいっていってたよね。本当に着てみない？
You know, you said the other day that you wanted to try wearing a dress. Do you want to actually try it on?
えっ？！着れるの…？！！！
What?! I can wear one...?!!!
朝になったら
When morning comes,
二人目を合わせて
we'll look into each other's eyes,
たわいないこと
and about silly things,
少し話したいな
I want to talk a little.
晴れた午後は
On a sunny afternoon,
そっと手をつないで
let's gently hold hands,
穏やかな街を
and through the peaceful town,
少し歩いてみたり
maybe take a short walk.
そんな想像さえ
Even a simple daydream like that
愛おしくて
is so precious to me,
いつまでも同じ時間を
wishing we could always
一緒に過ごしていたくて
spend the same time together.
だって
Because,
朝も
both in the morning
夜も
and at night,
伝えたいことたくさんあって
there are so many things I want to tell you.
今日も
Today,
明日も
and tomorrow too,
好きだなんて
if I could say "I love you"...
言えたら
If only I could.
夜になったら
When night falls,
星の見える場所で
in a place where we can see the stars,
眠りにつくまで
until we fall asleep,
ずっと寄りそっていたいな
I want to snuggle close to you.
触れられる距離が
This distance where we can touch
愛おしくて
is so precious to me,
その声をその体温を
your voice and your warmth,
もっと感じていたくて
I want to feel them even more.
だって
Because,
何度も
no matter how many times
and how many times
名前を呼んでもまだ足りなくて
I call your name, it's never enough.
今日も
Today,
明日も
and tomorrow too,
そう二人で
if the two of us can just...
いれたら
be together like this.
切ないときは綺麗な
When we feel sad, let's decorate with beautiful
花を飾りましょう
flowers.
悲しいときは楽しい
When we feel down, let's have a fun
話しをし
conversation.
...ましょう
...let's do.
髪に 頬に
In my hair, on my cheeks...
ただ触ってくれるだけで
...just by you touching them...
暗い心も
...even my dark heart...
瞬間 明るくなるんだって
...instantly brightens up, they say.
朝も 夜も
Whether morning or night,
叶えたいこと こんなにあって
there are so many wishes I want to make come true.
今日も 明日も
Today and tomorrow too,
幸せだと言えたら
if only I could say that I am happy...
いいのに
...that would be so nice.
メルは あなたのこと 愛しています
Mel loves you.
みんなー！
Everyone!
ここまで歌ってきましたけど どうですか？
I've sung up to this point, but how was it?
楽しんでますか？
Are you enjoying yourselves?
ここで 恒例のね
And now, for the usual...
みんなお待ちかね 告知タイムに行きたいと思います！
...which you've all been waiting for: announcement time!
もう5年目になるので みんなも大体流れ分かってきたよね？きっとね！
It's my 5th year already, so you probably know how this goes, right?
そう、正解！
Yes, exactly!
なんと！
And...
このあと 夜空メル5周年グッズが 販売されます！やったー！
...right after this, Yozora Mel's 5th-anniversary merchandise goes on sale! Yay!
イェーイ！
Yay!
まず 1つ目は
First off, the first item is...
さとうぽて先生描き下ろし アクリルスタンド！
...a newly drawn acrylic stand by Satopote-sensei!
なんと このアクリルスタンド ゆらゆら揺れるようになっております！
Amazingly, this acrylic stand is designed to sway back and forth!
すごい！可愛いよ！
It's amazing and so cute!
それからね 純白のドレス めちゃくちゃ可愛いので ぜひゲットしてください！
And that pure white dress is super cute, so please make sure to get it!
そして 2つ目は
And the second item is...
ミシュネ先生描き下ろしの メルと始める新生活クッション！
...the "Start a New Life with Mel" Cushion, newly drawn by Mishune-sensei!
表裏どちらも ガチ恋距離のメルちゃんがいます！
On both sides, Mel is at a heart-throbbing distance!
気分でお好きなように使ってください！
Please use it however you like depending on your mood!
君の生活の一部に メルを置いてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you'd let Mel be a part of your daily life!
そして 3つ目！
And thirdly!
メルと契約ネックレスです！
The "Contract with Mel" Necklace!
アクセサリー物は 実はメル初めてなので
This is actually my first time releasing an accessory,
ぜひこれも着けてほしいな
so I really want you to wear it.
男の子も女の子も着けやすいデザインに メルが監修させていただきました！
I supervised the design to make it easy to wear for both boys and girls!
イェい！どや！
Yay! Check it out!
これ あとね みんな気付いたかな？
Also, did everyone notice?
今回のメインイラスト 実はね メル着けてるんだ！
Mel is actually wearing it in this main illustration!
なので これを着ければ メルとお揃い！
So if you wear this, we'll match!
そして メルとずっと一緒にいようねっていう契約も 結んだことになるので
And it also means you've signed a contract to be with Mel forever,
ぜひ こちらもゲットしてください！
so please get this one too!
そして フルセットで購入してくれた方には
And for those who purchase the full set...
メルの直筆サインが
...you will receive a postcard...
つくポストカードがもらえます！
...personally autographed by Mel!
やったー！
Yay!
複製メッセージも付いてますので
It also includes a printed message,
こちらもね お早めに！数量限定になってるので お早めにお願いしますね！
so grab it quickly! It's limited quantity, so act fast!
グッズはこのあと 21時から販売されます！
The merchandise will be available starting at 9:00 PM!
心を込めて 今回もカキカキしますので よろしくお願いします！
I'll sign each one with all my heart, so please look forward to it!
それではね 次の曲で最後になるんですが
Well then, the next song will be the last one, but...
しかーし 今回も メンバー限定でアフターライブを開催しちゃいます！やったー！
However! We'll hold a members-only after-live this time too! Yay!
よかったら 君も かぷ民にならないか？
If you'd like, won't you become a Kapumin too?
なので 今のうちに メンバー登録もよろしくお願いします！
So, please join the membership in the meantime!
あっという間のライブでしたけど
It was a concert that went by in a flash,
5年目も もっともっと いろんな人が楽しんで メルのことを好きになってくれるよう
but in my 5th year, so more people can enjoy and come to love Mel,
ホロライブを引っ張っていけるように 頑張りますので こんなメルを...
I'll do my best to help lead Hololive, so please support me...
...だけど
...but
それからもよろしくお願いします
Please continue to support me from now on too.
みんなのことが好きな気持ちを最後まで込めて
Pours my love for everyone into it until the very end...
次の曲、歌います！
I will sing the next song!
合いの手もよろしくお願いします！
Please join in with the call-and-response, too!
はい！はい！え、ち、
Yes, yes... O-one...
…ねえ、どうかな？似合ってる？
...Hey, what do you think? Does it look good?
うん、綺麗だよ
Yeah, you look beautiful.
ふふーん、ありがと！でもまさかこんな早く着れるとはな〜！
Hehe, thank you! But I never expected to wear it this soon!
写真だけだけどね…
Though it's just for a photo...
いやーまさかメルプロポーズされたのかと思っちゃったよ
Gosh, for a second I thought Mel was getting proposed to!
いつか…ね
Someday... right?
ん？なんか言った？
Hmm? Did you say something?
いや！なんでもない
No! It's nothing.
（やっぱりメルは深夜アニメの主人公なのかもしれない。）
(Mel really might be the protagonist of a late-night anime.)
あ、そうだ。お礼に…これ受け取ってほしいな
Oh, right. As a thank-you... I want you to have this.
え？これは…？
Eh? What is this...?
これはね、代々伝わる大切な人に渡すネックレスだよ。
This is a necklace passed down through generations to be given to someone precious.
メルとずっと一緒にいる契を結んだ者だけがつけることができるのだよ！
Only someone who has pledged to be with Mel forever is allowed to wear it!
なにそれこわ！！！ていうか中二病感凄いんだけど！？
What's with that scary stuff?! Also, the chuunibyou vibes are off the charts!?
うるさい！！！！ていうか！いるのいらないの！？どっち！
Shut up!!! Anyway, do you want it or not?! Which is it!
…うん、ありがとう。ありがたく受け取らせていただきます
...Yeah, thank you. I will gladly accept it.
よろしい。メルとおそろいだよ！
Very well. Now you match with Mel!
これからもこんな私だけどよろしくね。大好きだよ
Please continue to support me, even though I'm like this. I love you.
メルは少し照れながらかしこまった口調で微笑んだ。
Mel smiled with a formal tone while looking slightly embarrassed.
誰と会ってた？って
Who were you meeting with?
浮気した？って
Are you cheating on me?
子供じゃないんだし
I'm not a child, you know.
秘密くらいあるよ
Even I have some secrets.
全部なんて見せてちゃ続かない
If I show you everything, we won't last.
ケンカしてても
Even if we fight,
隣り合って寝ること
sleeping side by side...
これからの約束ね
That's our promise from now on, okay?
返事！
Your answer!
幾つになっても 恋させてよ あなたに
No matter how old I get, keep making me fall for you...
格好悪いとこは 見ないようにしてあげるね
I'll try my best not to look at your uncool side, okay?
冷めていいけど 恋していて 私に
It's okay to cool down, but keep loving me...
綺麗だねと言われるように 頑張るからね
I'll do my best so you'll tell me, "You're beautiful."
様々な事があった日
On days when all sorts of things happened,
下手な料理で
With my clumsy cooking,
笑顔をありがとう
thank you for making me smile.
合わない趣味ばかり
We have nothing but clashing hobbies,
もっと教えて
tell me more about them.
こないだの続き
The continuation of what we talked about last time.
家族増えても
Even if our family grows,
恋人がいいの
I still want us to be lovers.
お揃いも増やしてよ
Let's get more matching things too.
返事！
Your answer!
幾つになっても デートしてよ 記念日
No matter how old we get, go on dates on our anniversaries.
プレゼントはいらない程 お洒落してね
Dress up so nice that I won't even need a present.
晴れでもいいけど 雨の日には くっついて
Sunny days are fine, but on rainy days, let's cuddle close.
一つの傘揺らしながら 虹を待つの
Holding a single umbrella as we walk, waiting for the rainbow.
気付いてた？
Did you notice?
寝てる隙に ほっぺにそっと キスしてること
That I gently kiss your cheek while you're asleep?
気付かなかった
I didn't notice.
寝てる隙に してくれてた
You were doing that while I was asleep...
...ダーリン ダーリン
...Darling, Darling
しわが増えても
Even if I get more wrinkles,
甘えたいんだよ
I still want to act spoiled.
もちろん手もつなぐこと
And of course, we'll hold hands too.
返事！
Answer me!
いくつになっても飽きないでね お願い
No matter how old we get, don't grow tired of me, please.
叱っちゃうけど頭撫でて 慰めてね
I might scold you, but pat my head and comfort me.
いつまでもずっと恋していて 私に
Keep falling in love with me, forever and ever.
「綺麗だね」言われるように頑張るからね
I'll do my best so you'll say, "You're beautiful."
みんなのおかげで5周年を迎えられたよ！
[Letter: Thanks to everyone, I reached my 5th anniversary!]
これからもたくさんの楽しい思い出つくっていこうね
[Letter: Let's continue to make lots of fun memories together!]
Big LOVE♡だいすき！！
[Letter: Big LOVE♡ I love you so much!!]
夜空メル
[Letter: - Yozora Mel]
みんなのおかげで5周年を迎えられたよ！
Thanks to everyone, I reached my 5th anniversary!
これからもたくさんの楽しい思い出つくっていこうね
Let's keep making lots of fun memories together!
Big LOVE ♡ だいすき！！
Big LOVE ♡ I love you so much!!
メル
— Mel